there's a mystery on the hermitcraft
server in today's third episode and it's
not who's been stealing everybody's
crops or where have all the parrots gone
or even who has the best hobbit hole on
the server
the biggest mystery that i still don't
know the answer to to this very day is
why this arrow
is flying
in this bamboo and i thought oh okay
this is just a bug magic flying arrow
doesn't do anything but no this has been
here all week since the server started
this has been flying
right here so just to prove it i'll
disconnect and reconnect boom
still there
mystery arrow
what are you i've literally never seen
this before i also don't want to destroy
this bamboo this bamboo is sacred i
think if this gets removed if it gets
touched this this arrow might go away so
uh we'll leave a sign telling people
arrow of mystery do not touch
super weird looks like scar has been
busy he's added a chimney to his snail
he hasn't removed the mustache so that
must mean that he uh he improves anyway
let's crack on with today's episode
because i've actually been making quite
a bit of progress and i want to continue
working on my hobbit hole
i've been thinking
the heck is this
whoa
[Laughter]
if you're such a hobbit
then you'll love this mordor
okay i didn't see it that's meant to be
the eye of sauron right there
and this is
more
door it's kind of got a it's kind of got
a team going on
this is absolutely amazing oh my
goodness i wasn't expecting that today
but he must have done this while i was
sleeping because look i've made some
yeah i gotta stop this i gotta stop the
night how do i let me in let me in
let me in
let's go around the
back they're all on individual timers
well played mumbo
well played
oh my goodness
more
water oh man i'm afraid that that
doesn't quite fit with what i was going
for i'm gonna have to build over there
later so i'm gonna have to remove the
more door but i think we need to keep
like a little museum of this because
this is amazing
so yeah as you can see i was looking at
this last episode now saying that
there's some issues that i couldn't
quite put my finger on and it was this
it needed some windows either side of it
and then sort of more grass on the top
so the little hobbit hole is coming
along quite nicely but there's actually
there's a lot more work that i want to
do to it and i want to get cracking on
all the stuff on the inside as well lots
and lots of progress that needs to
happen in today's episode
but first i think we need to we need to
take down um the the
high of sauron
the the mordor tower
oh my goodness
so why don't we kick off today's episode
with a really quick time lapse of some
improvements to the hobbit hole and
we'll take the ring to mordor
let's get on with it so unfortunately
the more door had to go and that's
because it needed to make way for some
more hobbit hole action now just above
the main door i edited that window into
the enchanting room because it just
didn't quite feel right i added birch
into everything else and that was still
sitting there with spruce the other
thing i did was sort of shaved off a lot
of the cliffs so they're not just
sheer steepness they actually have that
hobbit hole
smoothness over the top a really nice
hill which i'm building over the top of
this bit here and on this bit i wanted
to create something more curved and
organic looking to sort of match how the
shape of the hill goes but around the
corner and all in all i think it's come
out pretty pretty well
i'm pretty happy with how this has come
out actually it's almost going to become
a hobbit city hobby holes are meant to
be you know simple they're meant to be
like basically that one on a hill but
i'm turning it into something like a
fortress but i'm enjoying where this is
going and
i feel like i'm definitely not done yet
i could maybe add a bit more color in a
bit more to this color scheme add a bit
more trees but you'll see i've got a
room around the back here because
i know that we've just done a time lapse
but i essentially want to get a lot done
in a very short amount of time i need to
start making this a bit more productive
while i started working on this i
discovered literally the biggest cave
when i was uh doing this so i mean this
is dangerous
he took a while to explode there it's a
little bit dangerous in here but do you
know what this actually might save me a
huge amount of time i could use this
space as a mob farm because well i won't
have to mine out nearly as much as i
would normally so i'll create my cactus
farm maybe next episode we can work on a
a mob farm somewhere along the line this
could be really really good actually i'm
a little i'm a little scared to go over
there that's a lot that's a lot of
glowing stuff
so anyway let's crack on with this time
lapse we're not going to do the mob
this is such a good cave
it's so rare to find such a large space
like this
okay then let's crack on with this time
lapse and get going so for this little
time lapse i just wanted to create a
very simple farm but often it's the
farms like this that end up taking a lot
of time here's a pro tip if you're going
to be creating a farm like this don't
bother surrounding it in birch it's just
such a waste of time
just leave it as stone because i
realized no one's even gonna see it
and this ladies and gentlemen is why it
takes me four days to make an episode i
spent an entire day
making a stupid cactus farm and you know
what i realized i don't even really need
cactus at the moment but it is churning
out the cactus and it actually gave me
so much cactus fairly quickly that i
just decided to turn this into a little
composting machine while i'm at it so
that it can give me bone meal which i
can use for various things and then
while i was here you know i got a bit
carried away and i decided to add some
sugar cane and things got a bit out of
hand now you might be wondering why
didn't i just use a zero tick redstone
farm and that's basically just a piston
machine that creates this sort of thing
at tip top speed way way faster and more
efficient than what i just did there the
reason is that this is passive i don't
have to turn it on i don't have to turn
it off it will just slowly gather all of
the resources and most of all
it doesn't go
you know the crazy crazy noise that all
of those redstone machines make
yeah this just goes every now and again
it just makes a little noise like uh
so i opted for this design just just for
the peace of mind this is a peaceful
hobbit hole for the time being in fact i
spent so long on this i got distracted
from what i was wanting to do
now professor beacon i have been uh
we've been discussing things and
we want to make peace we are a peaceful
hobbit under here under this uh under
this house here so we want to give mumbo
jumbo a little gift no like genuinely a
little gift he's been rocking some iron
armor now i saw it in his video and i
thought it would be really nice
if i got him some enchanted diamond gear
i mean he's just gonna get what he gets
it's not it might it'll be only like you
know base level stuff he can add stuff
as he goes along
that was pretty bad
oh boy oh that wasn't that wasn't great
no that's not great hold on have i got
anything here protection you know what
that was pretty bad why don't we go into
the nether gather some quartz for some
more xp
and then try that again and we can
combine because i mean that that's
that's an insulting amount of shoddy
enchanting going on there so all right
let's go into the nether and gather some
quartz
[Music]
okay i hope he gets lucky this time
because i'm not doing this again
no oh man
oh that was a little bit better okay
we've got at least oh this is much
better either way we've got enough
diamond just to give mumbo his stuff he
can he can sort out the enchantments
later i'm sure he's going to be
basically on the grind for some sort of
villager farm anyway but what i wanted
to do was
yes i want to give him a present but i
also want to deliver it in a fun way so
i want to create a hobbit tunnel that
goes all the way to mumbo's base so i
have a quick and easy way to travel to
mumbo's base
and the best thing is even though he's
online he's gonna have no idea what
we're up to so time to tunnel all the
way over to mumbo jumbo's base
you know
i seriously regret
the things that i'm doing this early in
the season without a beacon without any
real thought into this i mind
uh well what is this three three by
three but then a bit more as well
and i'm even going to decorate i'm
really committing to this hobbit tunnel
to link up miner mumbo's base and the
best thing is he has no idea he has no
idea and i can't wait for him to
discover i'm not going to tell him of
course i'm just going to let him
discover this on his own so now i've got
to fill all this in with some spruce
wood and the thing is this is so about
three times longer than i expected it to
be
but it's not just even the mining out
that takes a long time i mean look at
that it's it's collecting all the wood
and it's storing all the bits that
you've mined
look at this
ridiculous
i made it all the way to the end
and then what you will find
is that i have got
a small room
and i am just on the other side of
mumbo's base you can see there that's
his enchanting room and you can even see
the particles of the portal here
see
we are literally
right on the other side of mumbo's base
yeah wait he hasn't got rid of my face
but look at this we are right here so
we'll let him discover this on his own
but uh first i thought what we could do
is um and basically another hobbit hole
because if you want to be a real hobbit
a hobbit like me then you've got to make
a hobbit hole within a hobbit hole
and that's exactly what we're going to
do it's not going to be a particularly
uh big house that we're going to make
here but it will be enough for him to
know what's going on
there we go that is the entrance to our
hobby hope there's not a lot of space up
there but hopefully that will pretty
much do it i'm gonna have to go and
gather some other resources but the
great thing about what i've just done is
i'm gonna have to make several trips
back and forth anyway
because i've got so much spruce wood to
place in this tunnel because i'm
committing to the design
and this is going to take a lot of back
and forth
oh blimey i'm going to need a lot of
stuff
this is going to
be not too pleasant to make to be honest
with you and back we go again
and we're back again we can do a bit
more of the hobbit hill that we're gonna
need here we don't need anything too
fancy to be honest just a simple hobbit
hole will suffice this has just got to
be a cave but the one true hobbit
is the hobbit that makes a hobbit hole
within a hobbit hole
so we need to make sure that the walls
aren't too flat here we want we kind of
you know we want this to look fairly
neat and tidy in here it's got to be a
nice discovery for him and that's the
same for the floor we can't have a stone
floor in a hobbit hole it's just not
happening there we go we'll let the
grass spread
and this isn't looking too shabby as
soon as we get some more greenery on
here this is gonna look more and more
like a hobbit hole there we go and now i
just need to add a couple of doors in
here and bingo bango but we gotta we
gotta go all the way back a little
progress here and then we go back
i hope we got enough spruce to see us
all the way because that would kind of
ruin the effect all right let's go
ah didn't quite make it but you can kind
of appreciate just how much spruce wood
i've had to chop down in order to make
this silly little tunnel
we also want to make sure that this
little house looks pretty good because
it's a secret within a secret within a
secret this is a secret base and then
this is going to be a secret entrance or
a secret tunnel to my base so it's it's
uh i think this is all three secrets
wrapped in one
it's a little cozy in here but that's
not a problem
all right let's do another road back
this tunnel's gonna kill me this tunnel
is gonna be the end of me six hours on a
cactus farm
and now i i don't even know how many
hours this has taken
you know what i'm just gonna i'm just
gonna go ahead and finish this and i'll
i'll be back in a second okay
oh my goodness
finally done
tunnel complete jeez this is such a long
tunnel and
i seriously regret
making it this fancy it doesn't it
doesn't need to be this fancy
and we turn the corner
and you're probably wondering why am i
doing this well i need to install
something at the end for all of this to
make sense
and that's where we're going now it's
just taking a while
this is kind of a weird effect it looks
like i'm traveling really slowly but i'm
moving faster than walking okay so up
here and then
it will drop
into mumbo's base but that's not for me
that's not for me
this is for something else
so what i need to install here is
actually a spot of redstone
i need a detector rail
and this is going to be really really
easy to do
and it should be as simple
as that a piston activated we put that
on
it it retracts the piston
oh wait no that doesn't work at all
okay so i definitely need a double
piston extender which makes this
more complicated than i originally
thought
but that's nothing
for me
i can do redstone now
ain't ain't it's not a problem
things like this scare me
i think this works it's just all about
timings right
huh
double piston extenders suck i'm gonna
learn that another time i'm gonna try
and tackle this a different way
oh my goodness i did it i just through
sheer
trial and error i don't this is not good
redstone i need to learn some things at
least i'm highlighting the gaps in my
knowledge but for some reason
this works and i ain't i am not messing
with it anymore
oh my goodness okay so let's just check
this out and make sure that it is fully
functional and i'm not just crazy
so the idea is to be able to send mumbo
messages with a minecart in a chest
that's the whole point of this so if we
push it along it will go through very
i don't know why but this isn't working
and it is driving me insane i haven't
got time to mess with this
will it just work with a hole in the
ceiling
and just this piston here please
there we go there we go job done the
simplest solution
job done
only a real hobbit makes a hobbit hole
inside a hobbit hole
also i linked our bases and it took me
all day okay thanks
let's go back to the base
because i want to make sure that this
works i will absolutely want to make
sure that this works
because i mentioned earlier we actually
made this to send mumbo a gift obviously
this is going to connect our bases it's
going to be a lot of fun blah blah blah
but i want to give him his diamond gear
so
we're going to send it in style and see
if he figures it all out there we are
it's not the best ah diamond armor ever
but it will definitely definitely do
okay we got our minecart
we got there
we'll put all of this in here
and a note saying a gift from the other
hobbit and then we just push it away
message sent to mumbo jumbo it takes a
few minutes to get there but when it
does it should arrive safe and sound and
just to prove it
there it is on the camera account if the
it had the gift has arrived safe and
sound and he may not realize one that
we've changed behind the portal to dirt
or two that we've created a full-on
message delivery system right behind his
base look how crazy this tunnel is it's
so
long
oh my goodness i could have saved some
time going diagonally but that would
have been a pain to build
so the last thing to do on this is to
just quickly
cover up
the last remaining bit of stone i mean
i've really committed to the whole
spruce interior so
yeah i've got to see this through
mumbo is actually online but i uh i can
confirm he hasn't received his gift yet
don't know i think i don't think he's
been at his base which is great for me
because i've managed to make this whole
thing without him even realizing
the other great thing about this is i i
will be able to send random messages to
mumbo just at any time
i don't i don't know what i'm gonna send
but just you know i can send him
presents or anything
oh man oh no he's there oh
i've just been casually placing some
leaf blocks
uh i hope he didn't see me i haven't
been crouching the whole time i think i
think that's him getting uh getting his
gift
i think he might have seen me oh no
oh yeah he was facing me
[Music]
i don't even think he's seen me
[Laughter]
i'm out i'm i'm out
i'm out of here
bye bye bye bye
bye
[Laughter]
the hobbit tunnel what a marvelous
invention
well the surprise didn't last long but
it was so worth it to see him do like he
did the smallest of double takes he was
like well there's agree in there i'm
gonna write him a quick message
hi mambo don't have any
oh
oh he's he's here he's used the
transport
oh he's he's giving me give me that is
that is this for me are you gonna put
the put the diamond on are we hobbit
bros
and then you go bye bye
that tunnel took so long
i'm glad he likes it i'll just i'll
finish the message anyway hope you like
a new hobbit
tunnel i shall send you
random things sometime
so it's as simple as sending a message
like this i mean soon i'll have books
that i'll be able to send him but look
hi mumbo don't have any books hope you
like our new hobbit tunnel i shall send
you random things and messages sometimes
i should probably sign that off oh you
know what and i'm also going to give him
some quartz
because why not
and away it goes
bye bye and with that i'm going to say
thank you very much for watching that is
definitely the end of the episode i am
pooped this has been a pretty intense
episode for me it took absolutely ages
to do all this stuff but my goodness are
we on to some amazing things this season
what is that wanted meanie bear head
bounty ten dive ten diamonds
oh man things are really starting to
kick off on the season seven server
and i love it i'll see you in episode
four good bye
bye bye